[theme music playing]
[tense music playing]
[screaming]
[shattering sound]
[Emilia] Today marks the death
of Miss Ivy Aguas!
[Ivy] What are you going to do?!
-Let me go!
-[Julio] Goodbye, Miss Aguas!
Let go! What are you doing?!
[Julio] You have outdone
yourself this time.
You have proven yourself
beyond all my imagination.
Truly you have Ardiente blood
running in your veins.
[Ivy] Help!
-Five, six, seven, eight…
-Help!
I'm down here! Somebody help me!
[Natalie] Choose where your loyalties lie.
With your friends? Or with me?
Them or me?
-[Diego] Dad, where is Ivy?
-[Raul] Ivy Aguas is in danger.
The Ardientes buried her alive.
You have to find and save her.
She only has a few hours left.
-[screaming]
-[glass breaks]
They buried her alive
just like what they did to me before!
[Damian] Now that I'm here, I'll help you.
[Ivy] I won't lose hope.
I believe in miracles.
What I want from you is the assurance
that Ivy Aguas is in that plywood box,
dead or alive.
If we have to dig up every grave,
so be it.
As long as we find her.
We have to find her, understood?
[Arthur] Wait! What if they gun us down?!
[Diego] We need to move!
We don't have time.
Ivy, we're here.
Don't worry, we'll save you.
Just hold on.
[Diego] There are guards everywhere,
but we can do this.
Thank you, Diego.
Don't worry, Ivy. We'll save you.
Hang in there.
I won't--
I won't let go.
[phone chimes]
[tense music playing]
[moans]
[labored breathing]
[foreboding music playing]
[man] Where are we headed to, boss?
How much will we get for this?
Just do as I say.
We just want to make sure
that our efforts
won't be for nothing, boss.
This mission is more important than money.
Madrigal.
Are we clear about this?
Your targets are Jaguar and the Ardientes.
-I haven't forgotten our deal.
-I'm just making sure.
So, what's the plan with Julio?
Are we going to send Emilia back to jail?
No.
Then what?
Ma'am, I know I am indebted
to you for saving my life.
But if you won't take advantage
of this opportunity…
let's just forget about our deal.
[tense music playing]
May we leave now?
Yes.
Let's go.
-[car engine starts]
-Follow them.
[foreboding music playing]
[Jose] Everything's set
for the centennial celebration, Governor.
Very good.
But I still want you to deploy
more bodyguards for me
as well as for Emilia.
We have to keep our guards up,
especially against Diego Torillo's ploys.
You know, I wonder…
Where does that bastard
get the guts he has now?
Maybe because Ivy Aguas
is on his side, sir.
[scoffs]
I already have Ivy Aguas.
I expect him to crumble and beg…
instead of going head to head with me
just to unseat me.
Not unless
he's got himself a new ally.
Colonel, I want you to find out
if there are other supporters of
Diego's complaint against me.
-[Jose] Yes, Governor.
-Go.
-Raul, where are you going?
-Papa.
Huh? Uh… I just have to…
meet a client of mine.
-Client?
-Yes.
All right.
[tense music playing]
[door closes]
-Come on! We need to act now!
-Just wait!
[Arthur] Who's that?
Hello, Dad?
Diego… Where are you, son?
I'll help you.
There's too many of them, Dad.
It's too dangerous.
Son, I helped you before,
and I will continue to do so.
Right now, we're the only ones
who have each other's backs.
So we need to work together.
I'm begging you, son. Let's work together.
Auntie…
There's still no update…
from Diego and Jepoy.
I'm sure they're just busy, Anna.
Yes, Auntie.
You're right.
Both Diego and Jepoy won't stop
until they save Lily.
They'll bring Lily home.
They'll find my daughter.
They'll dig her out of the grave
she's buried in.
Anna, Lily's been through so much.
This won't take her down.
[Camia weeps]
My daughter will live.
She, not the Ardientes, will live on.
She won't die at the hands
of the Ardientes.
Not to them.
[Camia sobbing]
[whimpering]
[weeping] Lily…
[sobs]
[breathing heavily]
[pensive music playing]
[pants]
[phone ringing]
[Emilia] Hello, Ivy!
I thought you were dead already.
Why, Emilia…
Did you miss me?
[chuckles]
Oh, it must be the other way around.
You're the one who misses me.
Because life down there must be so boring
with no company except darkness.
It gets so lonely, right?
Inside that box, I mean.
[chuckles]
[weakly] You know, Emilia,
you don't have to imagine it.
If you want,
we could trade places.
-Come on.
-[laughs] That's so funny.
And that will never happen, okay?
But, hey, let me tell you something, Ivy.
You know, according to research
a person buried alive
has only, like,
five and a half hours to live.
Then, after that…
hmm…
There can be suffocation,
disorientation, and dizziness.
If that happens, after all that,
you're going to die.
Oh! Poor Ivy.
And according to
my calculations right now,
you only got like an hour to go, and then…
-Bye-bye, cruel world!
-[thumps]
Oh! That must be so exciting
for you, Ivy, huh?
[thumps]
I know what you're doing.
You're trying to save your breath.
But time is running out.
-And here it goes…
-[moans]
Time starts now.
Tick-tock!
[laughing]
-[Emilia continues laughing]
-[pants]
[laughing]
[Ivy] Emilia…
[weakly] I'll repeat myself.
[emphatic] I'm Ivy Aguas.
I can handle everything.
-Remember?
-Okay. If you think that way.
But you know?
If you're going to be nice to me, Ivy,
who knows?
I might change my mind.
[weakly] Oh, Emilia.
You just never get tired
of talking, do you?
Is that all you want to say?
Because I don't want you
to be the last person I talk to if,
and only if,
I die today.
[Emilia] Hey!
You listen to me…
I know exactly what you're trying to do.
You're trying to save
your breath and your battery.
But I'm going to do the exact opposite.
I'm going to drain the air
out of your lungs
along with your phone battery
until you die!
And what makes you think that
you can get out of that grave?
No! You will be stuck there!
[laughs]
[sighs deeply]
[Diego] Batch, what now?
There's a dozen of them in there.
They all have guns.
We are no match for them!
I don't care!
We're going to save Ivy
no matter what happens.
All right. We're going to cripple them.
We're going to take them out
one by one. Let's go.
Batch, wait. Let's fall back.
There are too many of them!
If you want to go home, then go home.
I'm going to save Ivy.
-Wait.
-Diego!
[panting]
[goon 1] Just stay here for a bit.
-Okay.
-We'll stay here.
Keep your eyes peeled.
Don't let anyone get past you.
-[thwacks]
-[groans]
[suspenseful music playing]
[goon grunting]
Diego!
[goons grunting]
[goon 1] Sir! Sir!
-[goon 2] The other one!
-[goon 1] Yes, sir!
[goon 3] We have company!
You want to be heroes, huh?
[suspenseful music playing]
[clatters]
[tense music playing]
Our targets are Julio Ardiente's men.
You, go there! You two, there!
-Where?
-[thwacks]
[tense music playing]
[goon] This is the end for you!
-[Jepoy] Get down!
-[gunshots]
Diego!
[gunfire]
[goon] Retreat!
[gunfire continues]
Let's go! Come on! Come on!
[gunshot]
[tense music playing]
[Raul] What are you doing here?
Don't tell me you want
to join the party too.
[Damian] That's where you're wrong.
I'm here to help Ivy Aguas.
[gunfire]
[gunfire continues]
Jepoy!
[Marlon] Hide, Batch!
-Cover! Cover!
-Diego! Diego!
[gunfire continues]
[suspenseful music playing]
[Raul] Don't tell me you've
suddenly grown a conscience?
Do you really expect me to believe that?
You'll have to go through me
before you can do your plans.
I'm going to kill you first
before you can stop me!
[suspenseful music playing]
[both grunting]
You bastard! You can never
change who you are!
You can't! You are evil to the core!
Even the devil himself
would look up to you!
You're one to talk!
What's your reason for helping Ivy Aguas?!
Don't tell me you've grown
a conscience too!
A criminal will never trust
another criminal.
I will only trust you if you
show me your true identity.
[groans]
[both grunting]
[tense music playing]
[gunshot]
Diego?
[gunshots]
[ominous music playing]
[thumping]
Diego…
[pants] Die--
Diego, I'm here… [pants]
Jepoy! That's where Ivy is!
[gunfire]
-Are you sure she's there?
-Yes!
If Ivy isn't there,
we'll be wasting precious time!
I'm sure that's where they buried her!
-[gunshot]
-[Jepoy groans]
[gunfire continues]
[tense music playing]
[gun clatters]
[suspenseful music playing]
[laughs mockingly]
What, you actually thought you shot me?
Tough luck.
I told you we'd fight to the death, right?
[groans]
[gunfire continues]
[thumping]
You know what, Ivy?
Let me check again with you later, huh?
And don't you worry…
I'm going to give you your
moment to shine before you die.
Bye!
[exhales]
[gunfire in distance]
Diego!
Ivy's running out of time.
We need to hurry.
Hang in there, Ivy!
[thumping]
Diego…
Diego, I'm here!
[gunfire in distance]
[phone ringing]
Emilia?
Hello, Raul. Where are you?
Uh… On my way home.
[scoffs] Whatever, Raul.
Just come home, okay?
[tense music playing]
[phone ringing]
[phone continues ringing]
[line ringing]
[pants] Emilia?
Hi! Hi, Jaguar.
I--I missed you. How are you?
[groans]
Huh? Hello? What's wrong?
-Nothing's wrong, Emilia.
-Um…
I'll get back to you
again later, okay? Bye.
[tense music playing]
[panting]
Damn you, Damian.
[gunfire]
[pants]
[gunfire continues]
Kill them.
[gunshots]
There are enemies at the back! Retreat!
We're surrounded! We need to go!
Come on!
[gunfire continues]
They're retreating.
-Follow them! Hurry!
-[man 1] Come on!
Marlon, make sure
they don't come back here!
-[Marlon] I'm on it!
-You guys go with Marlon!
[Marlon] Come on! Come on!
[Jepoy] Ivy!
Ivy!
Hang on, Ivy!
[grunts]
-[men grunting]
-[shovels digging]
[Ivy] Mom…
Mom…
[instrumental theme music playing]
[somber music playing]
[Camia] Please watch over my daughter.
She still has to bring
those criminals to justice.
I'm begging you.
[men grunting]
[somber music continues playing]
[glass breaks]
Lily?
Ivy, we're coming!
[Diego groans]
[somber music continues playing]
[phone ringing]
[phone continues ringing]
[Emilia] Hello!
Are you still breathing?
Oh! According to my timer,
you've got one minute to live.
Oh, Ivy.
I do applaud your fighting spirit.
But you know? You always have
to remember that in life…
there's always a winner and a loser.
It just so happened now that
you are the loser, and your end
has come.
Goodbye, my dear.
[ticking sound]
[Emilia] So long, Ivy. Adios!
[moans]
Cheers to your life.
[laughing maniacally]
[Emilia continues laughing]
[screaming]
[Emilia laughing] This is so nice!
[laughs] Victory for me!
[laughing]
[raggedly breathing]
[dramatic music playing]
[tense music playing]
-[Anna] Diego, Jepoy!
-Anna!
Auntie Camia, they're back!
[both panting]
-Diego!
-Auntie.
Jepoy, where's my daughter?
Where's Lily?
[dramatic music playing]
[Camia breathing heavily]
[panting]
[Emilia] Lovely, I want my slit
a little higher.
And then, for the waist,
I want it like a corset.
Make it tight.
Because I'm on a strict diet, you know?
I want my waist accentuated, okay?
-And regarding Papa's barong…
-This is what he'll wear.
Hmm. Oh, well.
I'm positive he'll be
wearing a barong, okay?
-[Lovely] Okay.
-The food…
I'll discuss it tomorrow.
-Hi, Papa.
-Hi there, Emilia.
You seem to be in a good mood.
Oh! I am, Papa, in a very good, good mood.
Because our dark days are over, Papa.
How come?
Because our enemy, Ivy Aguas, is dead.
Isn't that supposed to be
a call for celebration?
Ivy Aguas is dead.
Are you sure?
I'm very, very sure, Papa.
I was there, listening to
her last breath, Papa.
In fact, my henchmen told me
that Diego Torillo tried to dig her out.
But they failed,
so I'm positive that Ivy Aguas is dead.
So, we should celebrate!
Yeah, seems like it's a good
reason for celebration.
Mm-hmm.
Good job, Emilia.
Thank you, Papa.
[Julio] You know…
we are going to have
the most amazing
centennial celebration ever.
And this will be the start
of a new chapter
of our reign over this province.
This will also mark our new beginning…
as father and daughter.
[chuckles]
Oh.
-Cheers, Emilia!
-Oh!
Cheers, Papa.
[Julio chuckles]
Excuse me, Papa.
I'll just fix our program.
Go ahead, go ahead.
[Emilia] Ladies…
Colonel!
Do you have any more good news to share?
Well, sir, I finally know
who's been supporting
Diego Torillo and encouraging
him to go against us.
-Who?
-Vice Governor Mateo Ruiz.
[chuckling]
These so-called goody two-shoes sure know
how to stab you in the back.
Anyway, I will deal
with that two-faced miscreant
of a vice governor.
Just wait and see.
[tense music playing]
[secretary]
This is for you, Vice Governor.
You may leave.
[tense music playing]
Governor! What a surprise!
Well, not as surprised as I am, Vice.
So, what are we discussing today?
[chuckles]
Let's cut to the chase.
You have been sleeping with the enemy.
Your enemy, Governor, not mine.
And here I thought you were different.
That despite our differences
in parties and principles,
you wouldn't dare snatch the position
I won fair and square.
But, no.
Now I find out…
that you'll even use
that amateur, Diego Torillo.
Now, that is a shocker.
It's a low blow…
considering you don't even
strike me as the ambitious kind.
That's true, Governor.
I'm not the ambitious type.
But I do have integrity.
Diego Torillo was the one
who approached me,
and I think it's for a good cause.
Oh, let's cut the political talk.
Let's just be real.
I'm helping Diego not because
I want to bring you down,
but because I believe in what's right.
Now, if the election really was rigged…
it's only right that you pay for it.
There's been news going around
that Julio's planning to move
his office to the capitol.
I also heard they're busy preparing
for the centennial celebration.
They say it'll be their victory party.
Those bastards!
If Lily were here,
there's no way she'd let Julio Ardiente
get away with rigging the entire election!
Then for her sake…
we won't give up.
We'll keep fighting and remove
Julio Ardiente from power.
We can't let my daughter's
sacrifices be for nothing.
[tense music playing]
Funny for you to be waving
the flag of justice,
when I know for certain that
at one time or another,
you did things you weren't proud of.
It being that you are an ex-military man.
Investigate me all you want.
You won't find anything.
I'm a straight-laced politician, Governor.
I've got news for you, Vice.
All politicians have their
fair share of dirty laundry.
It's just a matter of finding
the skeletons in your closet.
And believe me, I will find them.
If you don't stop this nonsense.
If I were you, Governor…
I'd postpone this celebration of yours.
You don't scare me.
[clicks tongue] Well then.
We'll just have to see about that.
Don't get on my bad side, Vice.
You won't like what you find.
[tense music playing]
[sighs]
[tense music continues]
I still can't believe it, Diego.
How could they do such a thing to Lily?
[sentimental music playing]
Don't give up, Anna.
Ivy would say the same thing
if she were here.
You know how she is.
She can take care of herself.
She'll keep fighting and never give up.
And that's why we can't, either.
Okay, I'll just go talk to the others.
[sentimental music continues]
Diego.
Tell it to me straight.
How do you feel about my friend, Anna?
-What are you--
-You know what I mean, Diego.
You're a guy. You know she likes you.
-Jepoy--
-Are you making moves on her
now that Ivy's gone?
Jepoy, I respect you as Ivy's friend.
So don't take my friendship
with Anna the wrong way.
There's only one woman I love.
And that's never going to change.
Remember that.
[tense music playing]
Oh, Raul.
Where were you, and what is that?
-It's nothing.
-Nothing?
It's too early for another fight, Emilia.
Excuse me, Raul.
Didn't I call you last night
because I was worried,
and this is how you treat me?
Wait.
Did you really call
because you were worried,
or is it because it's your
obligation as my wife?
And why are you always
so on edge when we talk,
but with other men, you're oh-so-sweet?
[scoffs] Have you been listening
to my calls?
No, why? Is it true
what they say about you?
Are you guilty?
Wow! Me? I think it's you who's guilty.
-You can't fool me, Raul.
-[scoffs]
You think I don't know that
you're working with Diego
and Ivy Aguas?
I already know, Raul, okay?
But I don't care.
It doesn't matter right now
because Ivy Aguas is dead, okay?
Oops.
Wait. Tell that to your son.
Ivy Aguas is dead.
[tense music playing]
All right, I'll see you both
at the capitol.
-Okay.
-Sure.
-Take care.
-We have to be there.
Take care.
[Damian] Camia.
Damian, where were you?
How's Ivy doing?
They buried my daughter alive.
How do you think she's doing?
I'm tired of crying and getting hurt.
The Ardientes need to pay
for what they did to my daughter
and this province.
[tense music playing]
[protesters chanting]
Julio Ardiente is a cheater!
Julio Ardiente…
Earlier today, Julio Ardiente
threatened Vice Governor Ruiz,
saying that he shouldn't support
my complaint against him.
We are sick and tired of all these threats
just to cover up the truth.
Julio Ardiente has to be ousted!
And pay for what he did
to this province, to Diego,
and to everyone who opposes him!
-Yeah!
-That's right!
-Impeach him!
[protesters chanting]
Julio Ardiente is a cheater!
Julio Ardiente is a cheater! Cheater!
Are you done yet?
[tense music playing]
You're like a broken record,
a pain to the ears.
But that's your right. Now, it's my turn.
First of all,
I would like to wholeheartedly
thank the citizens of Ardiente
who showed their love and support
so that your true leader
could assume office.
Now, for all my opponents,
the rivals that I've defeated,
those sore losers
who've done nothing
but find fault in my victory,
all I can say is, please be a good sport.
Truth is, you don't have anything on me.
You can keep complaining, but
the Ardientes will always win.
Because anyone who opposes you
ends up either dead
or buried in the ground!
Just like what you did to Ivy Aguas!
-Huh?
-[protesters] Yeah!
-That's right!
-He's right!
-Murderer!
-[Julio] Ivy Aguas?
Ivy Aguas was an ally.
She's been a big help to this election.
Why would I have her killed?
And don't forget, Diego…
Didn't I offer to lend you some of my men
to look for Ivy Aguas?
You liar!
[Julio] Huh? Oh, dear.
Camia, we didn't do anything wrong.
That's the truth. Just accept it.
Ivy's dead, and that's it.
So, to the loved ones of Ivy Aguas,
our thoughts are with you.
This is all I have to say…
It pains me to say this,
but the truth is,
Ivy Aguas played with fire.
And when you play with fire,
you usually get burned.
This is just a reminder to everyone,
so you won't end up like her.
You are a family of murderers!
[tense music playing]
Boss.
What are you doing here?
The men in our hideout
were talking about you.
They're wondering
if you're neglecting our operations.
Not now, Fabian. Leave me be.
Looks like your priorities
have changed, boss.
I hope you don't wait
for ours to change too.
[tense music playing]
Diego, Diego…
You never learn, do you?
After all those years
you lived in my house,
believing you were an Ardiente,
after all those years from your childhood,
you never learned anything
from me regarding politics.
Look at you now.
You're nothing but a pathetic sore loser.
You're the loser here.
You cheated in the election
because you were losing to me.
You couldn't accept the fact
that you were losing to a bastard like me!
[chuckling]
Diego, you're throwing pebbles
at a mighty wall.
But anyway, go ahead.
Keep accusing me.
Sue me if you want.
Do whatever you please.
But at the end of the day,
I will still be standing
as governor of Ardiente.
[camera shutter clicks]
[Julio] And if,
by some stroke of a miracle,
you manage to kick me out of my position,
just as you've been meaning to do,
haven't you realized that you
won't gain anything from it?
Because some Pontius Pilate will just
take advantage of all your hard work.
Don't you agree?
That's what you think.
Enjoy yourself while you still can.
Because mark my words…
I will make sure
to bring your family down.
My, my, Diego…
What's this? Are you hearing yourself?
What I see is rage.
Undirected, misguided rage.
Anyway, like I said, do whatever you want.
I will welcome all your accusations.
But in the end…
Julio Ardiente will still be the governor.
You're wrong.
Like I said, enjoy while you still can.
Because I will make sure…
I will make sure of
your family's downfall.
Well, good luck in
your endeavors, Diego Torillo.
But I'm telling you,
all your efforts will be in vain.
It's like riding a stationary bike.
You keep pedaling,
but you're going nowhere.
But I applaud you people.
Please, please continue
upholding your cause,
for what you believe in.
I will not stop you.
You have all the right
to voice out your opinions.
This is also to prove
that we Ardientes fight fair
and that we believe in democracy.
For now…
Please excuse me. Adios!
-[man] You cheated!
-[Loring] Cheater!
[protesters chanting]
Julio Ardiente is a cheater!
-[laughing maniacally]
-Julio Ardiente is a cheater!
-[Loring] Cheater!
Julio Ardiente is a cheater!
We report the passing
of renowned businesswoman
and a staunch supporter of
the Ardientes, Ivy Aguas.
This was confirmed by her
friend, Emilia Ardiente-Torillo,
who, at one point, almost
became her mother-in-law.
Any statement on Ivy Aguas'
passing, ma'am?
I had nothing to do with it.
I think I've answered
that question many times,
and I would still have the same answer.
I had nothing to do with it. Thank you.
[reporter] Stay tuned for more details.
[tense music playing]
Emilia.
Did you have Ivy Aguas killed?
And what makes you think that?
Oh, come on, Emilia.
I know my wife inside out.
You're a master when it comes
to dispatching people.
You know, Raul,
the reason why I'm still free
is that those people
have no evidence against me.
And that will also be the case
regarding Ivy Aguas' death.
[tense music playing]
Ivy may be gone now,
but I will never forget how she
helped us against the Ardientes,
especially when we were
almost killed by the governor.
I admire her even more now.
We shall see to it that her
efforts won't ever be in vain…
that they will continue
to haunt the Ardiente family.
[pensive music playing]
Sir?
What brings you here?
I have good news, Diego.
Election Commission Secretary
Martel has finally agreed
to hear out our complaints.
Thank you very much, sir.
Thank you too.
The media and Malacañang
noticed the noise you generated.
That's why we were given an audience
with the Election Commission.
We're going up against
a powerful man, Diego.
Are you sure about this?
I won't back out.
Everything's ready.
We're taking down Julio Ardiente.
[breathes deeply]
[sinister music playing]
No.
Come on, Emilia. [nervous chuckle]
This is not happening. Come on.
You're watching too many horror movies.
This is not happening.
[ominous music playing]
[suspenseful music plays]
[shudders]
[Ivy] Mark my words, Emilia.
If I die, I will haunt you.
[shrieking]
Papa! Raul!
[shrieks]
[suspenseful music playing]
Do you know what you're
getting yourself into?
I'm not scared
because I know someone powerful,
more powerful than that
politician you're protecting!
[Julio] Who else dared to go against me?
Lily Cruz.
I want you to hunt down Lily Cruz.
I want her dead!
[Jepoy] This is getting too risky, Anna.
If your life was in danger
before, it's worse now.
Dead people belong in the grave.
Who's this from?!
Get that thing away from me!
[Jose] What are you going
to do now? Jump off this cliff?
Or get shot?
[theme music playing]